<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Ernest Omane-Kodie</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Ernest Omane-Kodie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Drinking from the Firehose: using R to keep up with current ML Research - part 1</title>
      <link>/blog/drinking-from-the-firehose-using-r-to-keep-up-with-current-ml-research---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/drinking-from-the-firehose-using-r-to-keep-up-with-current-ml-research---part-1/</guid>
      <description>via GIPHYIn this post, I will explore how we can use resources available in the R package ecosystem to keep up with state-of-the-art machine learning research.
MotivationRecently, I have been reading books about creativity. The recurring concept in the books is that the key place to start when mastering a skill is by reproducing other people’s proven ideas and figuring out their inner workings - a form of apprenticeship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colours &amp; Impact: Resources for Data Visualization with a splash of R</title>
      <link>/blog/colours--impact-resources-for-data-visualization-with-a-splash-of-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/colours--impact-resources-for-data-visualization-with-a-splash-of-r/</guid>
      <description>via GIPHYA curated list of awesome data visualization resources with a splash of R. Inspired by Awesome R.
Arranged in no particular order.
Colour theory &amp;amp; chart designSubtleties of Color- Robert Simmon (2013)Make grey your best friend - Andy Kirk (2015)Viz Palette for Data Visualization Color - Elijah Meeks (2018)How to Optimize Charts For Color Blind Readers - Tom Jager (2017)The Do’s And Don’ts of Infographic Color Selection - Ryan McCready (2016)10 Do’s and Don’ts of Infographic Chart Design - Midori Nediger (2018)5 Data Visualization Tips to Guide Your Design Process - Jan Willem Tulp (2017)What to consider when choosing colors for data visualization - Lisa Charlotte Rost (2018)The Power of The Palette: Why Color is Key in Data Visualization and How to Use It - Alan Wilson (2017)Web toolscolororacle - Colour-blindness simulatorCanva Color Palette Generator - creates a palette based on the five main colours of any uploaded imageMaterial palette - converts any two colours into a full colour palette</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need for Speed: Benchmarks on Dataframes</title>
      <link>/blog/need-for-speed-benchmarks-on-dataframes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/need-for-speed-benchmarks-on-dataframes/</guid>
      <description>via GIPHYIn this post, I will explore the execution speed of various implementations of dataframe aggregation and combining operations in R.
I will record timings using microbenchmark, a package for measuring the performance of very small pieces of R code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Missing Packages from Bioconductor, CRAN and Github</title>
      <link>/blog/installing-missing-packages-from-bioconductor-cran-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/installing-missing-packages-from-bioconductor-cran-and-github/</guid>
      <description>via GIPHYOver the past few days I have had to use computers that are different from my trusty old laptop. One thing I noticed while working with R on the new machines is that the excitement in checking for, and installing, missing packages wears off pretty quickly. This blog post is a walk-through of a function I wrote to make the process less painful.
A bit more backgroundWhen R developers create open source packages, they typically distribute them through The Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN), Github or, if the package concerns computational biology and/or bioinformatics, Bioconductor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>