<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ernest Omane-Kodie</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ernest Omane-Kodie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Missing Packages from Bioconductor, CRAN and Github</title>
      <link>/blog/installing-missing-packages-from-bioconductor-cran-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/installing-missing-packages-from-bioconductor-cran-and-github/</guid>
      <description>via GIPHYOver the past few days I have had to use computers that are different from my trusty old laptop. One thing I noticed while working with R on the new machines is that the excitement in checking for, and installing, missing packages wears off pretty quickly. This blog post is a walk-through of a function I wrote to make the process less painful.
A bit more backgroundWhen R developers create open source packages, they typically distribute them through The Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN), Github or, if the package concerns computational biology and/or bioinformatics, Bioconductor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Ernest Omane-Kodie. I am at AXA where I use open-source technology, pricing and data science techniques to come up with answers to interesting questions around data.
I have learned a lot from the amazing rstats community over the years. I started this blog as a way of giving back through musings on the R programming language, data and visualisation.
This blog is built entirely in R using blogdown, and deployed with Netlify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>